This portion of the project runs the code on a weighted interactome. The weighted interactome was created by taking the portion of the FlyBase interactome created from the DroID database and searching that database to find weighted interactions. Thus, the FlyBase interactome is trimmed down to 27,431 weighted edges and 7,920 nodes. For comparison, the FlyBase interactome consists of 364,157 unweighted edges and 17,763 nodes, while the DroID portion of the FlyBase interactome consists of 262,179 unweighted edges and 11,442 nodes.

NOTES:

When running the code, the files required for the code must be in the same directory as the code..

DroID nodes were searched for weighted interactions at http://www.droidb.org/SearchGenesAction 

All files in the “DroID_Database_PPIs” directory were downloaded from the above website.

“DroID-flybase.txt” was taken from https://github.com/annaritz/fly-interactome/tree/master/databases/DroID


FILES:

“WriteUp.pdf” is the write up on the project addendum.

“DroID-flybase.txt” is the file of all the DroID interactions in the FlyBase interactome.

“DroID-flybase-ppis.txt” is an edited version of the above file with the extra information removed.

“DroID-flybase-nodes.txt” is a file containing all the DroID nodes in the FlyBase interactome. These nodes are used to search the DroID database for scored interactions.

“DroID_Database_PPIs” is a directory containing the raw files of weighted interactions downloaded from DroID.

“DroID-weighted” is a directory containing the above files after the extra information has been removed.

“all-DroID-weighted.txt” is a file that was created by taking the files in the above directory and combining them into one file.

“flybase-weighted-interactome.txt” is the weighted interactome.

“DroID-flybase.txt” and the “DroID_Database_PPIs” directory are the only things needed to run scoring_interactome.py. The remainder of the above files are created by running that code.

“positive-ids.txt” is the list of FlyBase positives.

“flybase-weighted-interactome.txt” and “positive-ids.txt” are the only files required to run bio331_project_with_weights.py.

“bio331_project_with_weights.py” was created by editing Anna’s version of the group project code. The only modifications made were to read in “flybase-weighted-interactome.txt” and to the function “read_edge_file” to correctly handle a file of weighted interactions. 

Running this code outputs 4 files:
1) “tree_nodes.txt” which is a list of Steiner tree nodes and Y/N to indicate if they are a terminal node

2) “tree_edges.txt” which is a list of Steiner tree edges

3) “new_shortest_paths.txt” which is a file containing non-positive nodes and all the positives that are found on the path to that non-positive node

4) “Dijkstra_rank.txt” which is a file containing a list of nodes and their BFS rank

These 4 files are needed to run “post_processing.py”. 

“nodes-flybase.txt” is also needed to run “post_processing.py” 

“post_processing.py” was taken from the group project, with the only minor modification being to the print statements to make the output more neat.

SANITY CHECKS:

“output1.txt” and “output2.txt” are two files containing the output from running “post_processing.py”. As a sanity check, all python files (“scoring_interactome.py”, “bio331_project_with_weights.py”, “post_processing.py”) were run two separate times from start to finish. The two output files are the exact same.

“Unweighted DroID FlyBase” is a directory containing everything needed to run the code on the unweighted DroID FlyBase interactome (Note: some files are the exact same files in its parent directory.) It also contains the output files from running the code.

“annas_edit_project_no_weights.py” is almost the exact same as “bio331_project_with_weights.py” except it takes in a different file and the “read_edge_file” function handles unweighted edges.

“output_unweighted.txt” is a file containing the output from running “post_processing.py”


